Chinh Le

Phone: 253-335-5485 | Email: chinh.ln1902@gmail.com | Portfolio: https://chinhln1902.github.io/

SUMMARY

A self-starter, independently motivated to overcome challenges, looking to leverage an internship and full-time job to gain experience and knowledge to advance my career while learning more about the industry. Confident in applying software engineering principles. Flexible, adaptable and able to work in changing environments.

I am an eligible US Permanent Resident (10 years Green Card) and already applied application for naturalization.

EDUCATION

University of Washington, Tacoma, WA

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Systems

Graduated June 2020

Award: Quarterly Dean's List Fall 2019 and Winter 2020.

COURSES & TECHNICAL SKILLS

Data Structures, Algorithms, Databases, Object - Oriented Programming.

Proficient in Java, C++, C, C#, SQL, HTML, JavaScript, ASP.NET, Python, R.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tata Consultancy Services

August 2020 - Present

Software Engineer

- Developing **forecasting** models in **Agile** environment. Cooperating with other team members to complete assigned user stories.
- Developing data models and visualize huge data sets to achieve business value. Generating forecast outputs using different **forecasting models** and evaluate the accuracy of the outputs using **R**.

University of Washington Tacoma

September 2019 – June 2020

IT and Library Assistant

- Collaborated with faculty and students with curriculum-related projects and administrative duties.

The Making A Difference Foundation

September 2018 – December 2018

Software Engineer

- Maintained **User Interface**, current features and developed new features for Check-in application in **Java**.

PROJECTS

Zombie

- Developed **AI** agents for a survival game simulation using **Javascript** and **A Star algorithm** so that agents can make decision between run away or kill appropriate zombies to survive as long as possible.

Tic Tac Toe

- Implemented an **AI** agent for Tic Tac Toe simulator to defeat all programmed agents using **Javascript** and **Minimax algorithm.**

Race Day

Developed a Java application to simulate a race of multiple people using Object Oriented Programming,
Graphical User Interface and Unit Testing.

Chat Application

- Created Chat Application on Android platform using Java, Web services that allow users to communicate.
- Implemented key features such as a **weather forecast module** to display current weather based on location.

The MADF Mobile Application

- Developed **Check-in** application on **Android platform** using **Java** to include features such volunteers check in and hourly schedule, in addition to tracking customer's allotted food.

ACTIVITIES: Member of HUSCII Coding Club, Attempted to UWT Hackathon Spring 2019.